Clemens Devarajan

Location: London

Email: dcleme51@gmail.com

PROFILE

A graduate in the discipline of Product Design with experience across hospitality, retail and the recruitment industry. Several years working in customer facing roles and now seeking to transition my career where I am able to challenge myself within the tech industry. At present I am actively undertaking a front-end web development bootcamp learning the trade and aiming to exploit the sector and to kick-start my career in a junior role within this field.

EMPLOYMENT

2014 - Present: Next Retail

Sales Consultant & Person in Charge/PIC

- Proactively assisting customers to ensure a positive experience in store, as well as keeping the shop floor replenished with best-selling goods.
- Involved in merchandising such planning the format of the menswear department and performing the necessary floor changes including preparations for sale periods.
- Further responsibilities as a PIC include supervising, training and supporting new starters and team members, assisting the delivery team and admin tasks such as auditing and banking and recruitment.

November 2022 - March 2023: Socium Technical Delivery Consultant

- Working across multiple start-up clients across UK and Europe sourcing and delivering high quality candidate profiles in a range of roles within Software Engineering.
- Use of the CRM database as well as sourcing tools such as LinkedIn, CV Library and CW Jobs to reach out to prospective candidates in qualifying for existing job roles with clients.
- Job posting and advertising roles to attract technical professionals to qualifying and vetting for clients prior to presenting them for their hiring options.

November 2021 - October 2022: Masentó Group (D&A Division) Technical Delivery Consultant

- Main responsibility to resource and qualify candidates working in the Tech sector within UK and DACH region.
- Specialised in Cloud Technology, Data, Ai & Automation as well as various Technical roles such as Software Engineers, Developers, DevOps and Architect positions for consulting clients.
- Other activities include Job Posting, Interview preparations and candidate management.
- Roles varied from salaries upwards of £/€ 60,000+
- Outcomes: Learning a new market and becoming quite adept especially the technical roles, development of communication skills with candidates; qualifying and building a good rapport, organisational skills and being resilient.
- Achievements: Four deals with average fee size of £/€ 18,500 to date with number of other processes in the pipeline. Hitting the quarterly directors clubs in my 2nd Quarter with the company.

April 2021 - October 2021: Health Recruit Network Trainee Recruitment Associate

• Learning the ways of recruitment on a 180 level. Gaining valuable experience in resourcing using their CRM system and job boards such as CV Library and Total Jobs. Speaking to Nurses of all levels and Home Managers of Care homes building rapport to help them find their next role. Learnt how to handle objections, negotiating and closing deals. I was involved in 13 deals with average fee size of £4,500.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2023 - 2024 EdX - Front-end Web Development Bootcamp

• Currently venturing into a new avenue to transition into the tech sector learning the fundamentals of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, APIs and aiming to develop these skills across the bootcamp.

2015 - 2019 Nottingham Trent University - BSc (Hons) Product Design

• Upper Second-Class Honours with Professional Practice

2012 - 2015 Richard Challoner and Holy Cross Sixth Form

A-Levels:

- Design and Technology
- Mathematics
- Information Communication Technology

2010 - 2012 Richard Challoner School

- 9 GCSEs at grades A-C including English and Maths
- BTEC LEVEL 2 ICT (Distinction*)

ADDITONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2019 Received a commendation from Hydro for undertaking a live project.
- 2019 Featured in the BBC East Midlands and the East Midlands Business News for my Major Project A study on developing countries and water scarcity.
- 2015-2019 Student Member of Institution of Engineering Designers (IED)
- 2013 National Citizen Service The Challenge
- 2012-2013 Being a director in the Young Enterprise company
- 2012 Gold in the UK Senior Maths Challenge

SKILLS

- Strong Communication Skills
- Relationship Building
- Marketing
- Objection handling
- Negotiating
- Team Player
- Leadership
- **Trilingual** English (Fluent), Tamil (Intermediate) & German (Conversational).
- Full Clean UK Driving Licence